Franz Waxman Papers
Franz Waxman Papers
- Recordings
  - Professional recordings
    - Mr. Skeffington (11 of 18), 10/22/1938; waxman_0093; Scenes 85-92; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Mr. Skeffington (12 of 18), 10/21/1938; waxman_0094; Scenes 57-63; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Mr. Skeffington (13 of 18), 10/21/1938; waxman_0095; Scenes 52-56; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Mr. Skeffington (14 of 18), 10/21/1938; waxman_0096; Scenes 42-51; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Mr. Skeffington (15 of 18), 10/21/1938; waxman_0097; Scenes 34, 36_1, 36_2, 37-39, 40_1, 40_2, 41; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Mr. Skeffington (16 of 18), 10/21/1938; waxman_0098; Scenes 26-33; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Mr. Skeffington (17 of 18), 10/22/1938; waxman_0099; Scenes 99-106; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Mr. Skeffington (18 of 18), 10/22/1938; waxman_0100; Scenes 93, 94_1, 94_2, 94_3, 94_4, 95-98; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Mr. X Concerto for Piano and Orchestra, waxman_1043; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - Music Festival, 1956; waxman_1000; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 121)
    - Music for Jazz Orchestra, Three Sketches, Theme, Variations and Fugato, waxman_0955; "Music by Franz Waxman"; 1/4 inch audio tape; running time 17:20 (Oversize 119)
    - Music by Franz Waxman, 9/25/1963; waxman_0957; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
      1. Sinfonietta for Strings and Timpani; 2. A Place in the Sun Suite
    - Music by Franz Waxman, waxman_0958; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
      1. The Horn Blows at Midnight, Athaneal the Trumpeter; 2. Goyana for Piano and String Orchestra; 3. Carmen Fantasy
    - Music In The Air, waxman_0426; picture Disc; Autographed by Performer; Shellac disc
      There's a Hill Beyond a Hill; I've Told Ev'ry Little Star; And Love Was Born; When The Spring is in the Air; We Belong Together; I:n Egern on the Tegern Sea; One More Dance; The Song Is You
    - [My Geisha], waxman_1103; part of Franz Waxman re-recording project 1970. Re-recorded by Walter L. Welch December 3, 1970.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
      My Geisha (Electrovox-Paramount Pictures non 10370 side 1 Main title, work Montage, You are sympathy to me. My Geisha (Electrovox-Paramount no. 10370 side 2 overture and first scene, love duet, one fine day, hara-kiri shooting version; My Geisha, Felix Slatkin (Liberty Records - United Recording corp. July 17, 1962 flat dub from mono master 45 rpm; Katasumi theme (Rockhill recording) 78 rpm
    - My Geisha, waxman_0423; paramount Pictures Soundtrack; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Main Title, Side A; Work Montage, Side A; You Are Sympathy To Me, Side A; Overture and First Scene, Side B; Love Duet, Side B; One Fine Day, Side B; Hara-Kiri, Side B
    - My Geisha, waxman_0813; Lacquer discs/acetates
      My Geisha theme
    - My Geisha, waxman_0956; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
    - My Geisha, 7/28/1961; waxman_0862; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 117)
    - Mysterious Deep, 1 Beginning, 3/11/1960; waxman_0863; Box 1; 60F132B; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 117)
    - Mysterious Deep, 1 continued, 3/11/1960; waxman_0864; Box 2; 60F1382; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 117)
    - Mysterious Deep, 2, music cues, 3/11/1960; waxman_0969; Box 3; (music cues); 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
    - NBC Symphony Conducted by Arturo Toscanini (Disc 1 of 5), 01/15/1938; waxman_0188; Orchestral Music; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Tragic Overture Op. 81
    - NBC Symphony Conducted by Arturo Toscanini (Disc 2 of 5), 01/15/1938; waxman_0189; Orchestral Music; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Symphony No. 2 in D
    - NBC Symphony Conducted by Arturo Toscanini (Disc 3 of 5), 01/15/1938; waxman_0190; Orchestral Music; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - NBC Symphony Conducted by Arturo Toscanini (Disc 4 of 5), 01/15/1938; waxman_0191; Orchestral Music; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Rondo Schezo Arlecchinesco
    - NBC Symphony Conducted by Arturo Toscanini (Disc 4 of 5), 01/15/1938; waxman_0192; Orchestral Music; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Carnival of Venice
    - NBC Symphony conducted by Toscanini (Disc 1 of 4), 01/22/1938; waxman_0184; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Overture "Anacreon"; Symphony No. 98 in B flat
    - NBC Symphony conducted by Toscanini (Disc 2 of 4), 01/22/1938; waxman_0185; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Symphony No. 98 in B flat
    - NBC Symphony conducted by Toscanini (Disc 3 of 4), 01/22/1938; waxman_0186; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Serenade in A Major Op. 16
    - NBC Symphony conducted by Toscanini (Disc 4 of 4), 01/22/1938; waxman_0187; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Serenade in A Major Op. 16; Prelude "Die Meister Singer"
    - NBC Symphony, 2/16/47 (1 of 2), 2/16/1947; waxman_0022; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - NBC Symphony, 2/16/47 (2 of 2), 2/16/1947; waxman_0023; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Never Lose Your Sense of Humor, waxman_0806; Vocal with piano accompaniment; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Never Lose Your Sense of Humor; Coni Coni; It's You
    - Neville Chamberlain Speech, 09/03/1939; waxman_0801; VinylDisc
      Chamberlain Speech
    - New Recordings from the films of Franz Waxman The Bride of Frankenstein - Botany Bay - Taras Bulba - Mr. Roberts - The Horn Blows at Midnight - The Paradine Case, 1986; waxman_0752; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
      Side One 1. The Horn Blows At Midnight "Athaneal The Trumpeter" Overture for Trumpet and Orchestra (6:45); 2. Mr Roberts Prelude - Main Title - Final Scene - End Cast (3:20); 3. Bride Of Frankenstein Dance Macabre (6:57); 4. Taras Bulba Cossack Brotherhood - The Wishing Star - Cossack Anthem - Zaparoshtchi (The Two Sons of Taras) Ay Lulee Lulee Rissian Lullaby - the Wishing Star - The Ride To Dubno 8:45; Side Two 1. Botany Bay Prelude and Foreward - Montage - New Escape Plot - Love and Victory 9:35; 2. The Paradine Case Fantasy for Piano and Orchestra 12:20
    - New Recordings From The Films of Franz Waxman: The Bride Of Frankenstein - Botany Bay - Taras Bulba - Mr. Roberts - The Horn Blows At Midnight - The Paradine Case, 1986; waxman_0739; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
      Side One 1. The Horn Blows At Miodnight "Athaneal The Trumpeter" Overture for Trumpet and Orchestra (6:45); 2. Mr Roberts Prelude - Main Title - Final Scene - End Cast (3:20); 3. Bride Of Frankenstein Dance Macabre (6:57); 4. Taras Bulba Cossack Brotherhood - The Wishing Star - Cossack Anthem - Zaparoshtchi (The Two Sons of Taras) Ay Lulee Lulee Rissian Lullaby - the Wishing Star - The Ride To Dubno 8:45; Side Two 1. Botany Bay Prelude and Forword - Montage - New Escape Plot - Love and Victory 9:35; 2. The Paradine Case Fantasy for Piano and Orchestra 12:20
    - Newman 755 #2, waxman_0674; 812: T1 - x, T2 - x, T3-x, T4-x, T5-0; 824: T1-x, T2-x, T3-0; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Next Time We Love, 01/06/1936; 01/08/1936; waxman_0532; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Main Title, Side A; End Title, Side B
    - Night Soliloquy, waxman_0625; Shellac disc
      Night Soliloquy, Side A; The White Peacock, Side B
    - Night Unto Night (1 of 4), waxman_0135; movie score; rehearsal recording; Lacquer discs/acetates
      side A, track 1 [unknown title]; track 2 [unknown title]; track 3 [unknown title]; track 4 [unknown title]; track 5 [unknown title]; track 6 [unknown title]; side B [unknown title]
    - Night Unto Night (2 of 4), waxman_0136; movie score; rehearsal recording; Lacquer discs/acetates
      side A [unknown title]; side B, track 1 [unknown title]; track 2 [unknown title]; track 3 [unknown title]; track 4 [unknown title]
    - Night Unto Night (3 of 4), waxman_0137; movie score; rehearsal recording; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Side A, track 1 [unknown title]; track 2 [unknown title]; track 3 [unknown title]; track 4 [unknown title]; track 5 [unknown title]; track 6 [unknown title]
    - Night Unto Night (4 of 4), waxman_0138; movie score; rehearsal recording; Lacquer discs/acetates
      side A, [unknown title]; side B track 1 [unknown title]; track 2 [unknown title]
    - The Nightingale Beginning, waxman_1030; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - The Nightingale Conclusion, waxman_1031; 1/4 inch audio tape
    - Norma, waxman_0446; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 17, Side A; Part 19, Side B [Is this from Sunset Boulevard? If so need to add that as title to all of these.]
    - Norma, waxman_0447; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 18, Side A; Part 20, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0448; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 21, Side A; Part 23, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0449; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 22, Side A; Part 24, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0450; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 25, Side A; Part 27, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0451; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 26, Side A; Part 28, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0452; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 29, Side A; Part 31, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0453; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 30, Side A; Part 32, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0438; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Norma, waxman_0439; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Norma, waxman_0440; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 5, Side A; Part 7, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0441; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 6, Side A; Part 8, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0442; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 10, Side A; Part 12, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0443; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 13, Side A; Part 15, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0444; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 14, Side A; Part 16, Side B
    - Norma, waxman_0445; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 9, Side A; Part 11, Side B
    - Noveau Bonheur, waxman_0262; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      Noveau Bonheur, Side A; Paris Je T'aime D'Amour, Side B
    - The Nun's Story: Original Academy Award Nominated Score, 1975; waxman_0736; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
      Side One 1. Prelude and Credo; 2. Leaving; 3. The Holy Order; 4. Farewell; 5. Ave Maria Stella; 6. I Accuse Myself; Side Two 1. Haircutting & Gran Coro; 2. Departure & The Congo; 3. The New Room; 4. Killing of Aurlie; 5. War Report; 6. Last Meeting & Finale
    - The Nun's Story: Original Academy Award Nominated Score, 1975; waxman_0737; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
    - The Nuns Story, recorded 01/05/1959; waxman_0783; Orchestral Music; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Prelude--main title (main theme), track 1, Holy Order, track 2, side A; Arch Angel, track 1, Killing Aurelie, track 2, side B
    - Oberon Overture, waxman_0406; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
    - Objective Burma, waxman_0025; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Objective Burma!; Paradine Rhapsody; Piano improvisations of early Waxman themes: Bride of Frankenstein, The Invisible Ray, East of Java, After the Storm; excerpts from Bride of Frankenstein, The Lost Command, waxman_0822; piano improvisations of early Waxman themes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 116)
    - Oedipus Rex, 06/06/1954 or 06/06/1962; waxman_1002; program celebrating the 80th birthday of Igor Stravinsky. 8:30pm performance.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 122)
    - Oedipus Rex, 06/06/1954 or 06/06/1962; waxman_1003; program celebrating the 80th birthday of Igor Stravinsky. 8:30pm performance.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 122)
    - Off Air Television dubs, waxman_0898; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 117)
      This is the Warner Brothers version
    - Off The Air Recorded Exerpts, Dubs, Soundtracks, waxman_0886; Off the air recorded excerpts, dubs; nothing original; soundtracks from films; exerpts; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 117)
      [unreadable]; Sorry Wrong Number; Elephant + Walk; Prince Valliant End Title; Come Back Little Sheba; Talk Fuse; He Ran All The Way
    - Old Acquaintance, 04/14/1943; waxman_0433; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 133)
      Love Theme, Side A
    - Old Acquaintance, 04/14/1943; waxman_0434; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 133)
    - Old Acquaintance, waxman_0675; String Orchestra; Aluminum Record
      old Acquaintance
    - Old Acquaintance, waxman_0580; Shellac disc
      Old Acquaintance, Side A; How Sweet You Are
    - Olive Mae Beach, waxman_0250; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Cosi Fam Tutte
    - On The Sunny Side Of The Street, waxman_0612; Shellac disc
      On The Sunny Side Of The Street, Side A; Flying Home, Side B
    - One Only Sees That in Paris, waxman_0590; Shellac disc
      One Only Sees That In Paris - Fox Trot, Side A; Without A Word - Waltz, Side B
    - Open Windows, waxman_0941; TV Pilot; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
    - Opening & Closing Announcements, 06/23/1946; waxman_0655; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Opening & Closing Announcements, Side A; Concerto for Violin, 1st Movement, Concluded, Side B
    - The Opera Ball, waxman_0610; "In Chambre Separee"; Shellac disc
      The Opera Ball, side A; Merry Widow - Waltz Song, side B
    - Original Film Score from "Beyond All Barriers", waxman_0740; Film Soundtrack; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Original Motion Picture Soundtrack: Hemingway's Adventures of a Young Man, 1962; waxman_0730; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
      Side One Prologue; Leaving Down; D.T. Blues; Goodbye Father; The Hospital; Side Two Rosanna; No Sleep; The Major's Rescue; Rosanna's Death; Home Again; Finale
    - Original Motion Picture Soundtrack: Hemingway's Adventures of a Young Man, 1962; waxman_0731; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
    - Original Motion Picture Soundtrack: Hemingway's Adventures of a Young Man, 1962; waxman_0732; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
    - The Original Soundtrack Album: Sayonara, 1958; waxman_0728; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
      Side One Opening; Sayonara Berlin 2:35; Eileen 5:35; Sakura Sakura Matsumoto-Kishimoto; By the Bridge; Sayonara Berlin 3:50; Katsumi Theme 3:22; Matsubayashi Theatre 4:52; Side Two Hana-Ogi 5:55; Sayonara Berlin 4:30; Street Fight 2:36; Death Scene; Sayonara Berlin 3:00; The Wig Room; Sayonara 3:14; Finale Sayonara Berlin 1:35
    - The Original Soundtrack Album: Sayonara, 1958; waxman_0729; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
    - The Original Soundtrack Album: The Spirit of St. Louis, 1957; waxman_0725; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
      Side One Prelude; Building the Spirit; First Test Flight; Flight to St. Louis; New York To Cape Cod; Nova Scotia; Spirit of St. Louis; Side Two The Old Jenny; Barnstorming; Fishing Boats; Ireland; Plymouth; Le Bourget; End Title
    - The Original Soundtrack Album: The Spirit of St. Louis, 1957; waxman_0726; Film Soundtrack; VinylDisc
    - The Original Television Scores Volume One The Twilight Zone, waxman_0743; VinylDisc
      Main and End Titles; The Invaders; Perchance To Dream; Walking Distance; The Sixteen-Millimeter Shrine
    - Overture and Bacchanale, Tannhauser; National anthems of US and Mexico, waxman_1053; 1/2 inch audio tape
    - Overture to Der Freischütz, Symphony No. 1, Movement 1, Jun 1960; waxman_0946; 8:30 pm performance at Royce Hall, UCLA; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
    - Overture to Euryanthe; Symphony No. 3 in E-flat Major, "Eroica"; Concerto Grosso; A Christmas Cantata, "Une Cantate de Noël", 12/17/1957; waxman_0855; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 116)
    - Overture to the Flying Dutchman; Symphony in D Major, 02/26/1938; waxman_0053; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Overture to the Magic Flute, 01/08/1938; waxman_0709; Shellac disc
      Overture to the Magic Flute, Side A; Symphonie No. 6, Side B
    - Overture to The Marriage of Figaro; Speech; Symphony No. 2 in C minor, part 1, 6/13/1960; waxman_0850; 8:30 pm performance at Royce Hall, UCLA; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 116)
    - Overture; Symphony No. 3 in Eb (Disc 1 of 4), 01/29/1939; waxman_0178; Orchestral Music; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Parade of the Wooden Soldiers, waxman_0298; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      Parade of the Wooden Soldiers, Side A; O, Ya Ya, Side B
    - The Paradine Case, waxman_0936; 1/4 inch audio tape; running time 11:33 (Oversize 118)
    - The Paradine Case, waxman_0954; Most likely a copy of above; 1/4 inch audio tape; running time 11:33 (Oversize 119)
    - The Paradine Case, waxman_0431; Lacquer discs/acetates
      A - 10 - Pt1 - Btk, Side A; A - 10 - PT2 - Btake, Side B
    - The Paradine Casee, waxman_0432; Lacquer discs/acetates
      A - 10 - Pt3 - BTK, Side A; A - 10 - Pt4, Side B
    - Parlez-moi d'amour Parlez-moi d’amour [commercial recording], waxman_0264; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      Parlez-moi d'amour, Side A; Dans la fumee, Side B
    - Pars, waxman_0257; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      Pars, Side A; Chanson De Marin, Side B
    - Pelleas et Melisande [parts unknown], 01/13/1945; waxman_0036; Metropolitan Opera; Bidu Sayao as Melisande; Martial Singher as Pelleas; Lawrence Tibbett as Golaud; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 130)
    - Pelleas et Melisande, parts 2 and 4, 01/13/1945; waxman_0038; Metropolitan Opera; Bidu Sayao as Melisande; Martial Singher as Pelleas; Lawrence Tibbett as Golaud. NOT TRANSFERRED; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 130)
    - Pelleas et Melisande, parts 5 and 7, 01/13/1945; waxman_0037; Metropolitan Opera; Bidu Sayao as Melisande; Martial Singher as Pelleas; Lawrence Tibbett as Golaud; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 130)
    - Pelleas et Melisande, parts 6 and 8, 01/13/1945; waxman_0040; Metropolitan Opera; Bidu Sayao as Melisande; Martial Singher as Pelleas; Lawrence Tibbett as Golaud; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 130)
    - Pelleas et Melisande, parts 9 and 11, 01/13/1945; waxman_0039; Metropolitan Opera. NOT TRANSFERRED; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 130)
    - Pelleas et Melisande [parts unknown], 01/13/1945; waxman_0041; Metropolitan Opera; Bidu Sayao as Melisande; Martial Singher as Pelleas; Lawrence Tibbett as Golaud; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Persephone (1 of 2), waxman_1082; 1/2 inch audio tape
    - Persephone (2 of 2), waxman_1083; 1/2 inch audio tape
    - Peter, waxman_0311; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      Peter, Side A; Jonny, Side B
    - Peus Seule Chaque Jour, waxman_0592; Shellac disc
      Peux Seule Chaque Jour, Side A; Mon Legionnaire, Side B
    - Piano Concerto, waxman_0779; Columbia Records Test Pressing; Shellac disc
      Piano Concerto
    - Piano Concerto, waxman_0780; Columbia Records Test Pressing; Shellac disc
    - Piano Concerto, waxman_0781; Columbia Records Test Pressing; Shellac disc
    - Piano Concerto in A Major; Dialogues for Jazz Combo and Symphony Orchestra, Jun 1960; waxman_0948; 8:30 pm performance at Royce Hall, UCLA; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
    - Piano Concerto in A Major; Dialogues for Jazz Combo and Symphony Orchestra, Jun 1960; waxman_0949; 8:30 pm performance at Royce Hall, UCLA; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
    - Piano Concerto No. 1, waxman_0768; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 1
    - Piano Concerto No. 1, waxman_0769; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 2
    - Piano Concerto No. 1, waxman_0770; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 3
    - Piano Concerto No. 1, waxman_0771; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 4
    - Piano Concerto No. 1, waxman_0772; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 5
    - Piano Concerto No. 1, waxman_0773; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 6
    - Piano Concerto No. 1, waxman_0774; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 7
    - Piano Concerto No. 1, waxman_0775; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Part 8
    - Piano Concerto No. 2 in F Major, Opus 102; La Valse, 6/2/1958; waxman_0851; 8:30 pm performance at Royce Hall, UCLA; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 116)
    - Piano Concerto No. 3 (1 of 2), waxman_1066; 1/2 inch audio tape
    - Piano Concerto No. 3 (2 of 2), waxman_1067; 1/2 inch audio tape
    - Pictures at an Exhibition (Disc 4 of 4), 01/29/1939; waxman_0181; Orchestral Music; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Piezas, waxman_0814; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Piezas
    - Piezas, waxman_0815; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Piezas, Side A; La Quadrilla Espagnol, Side B
    - The Pines of Rome, waxman_0407; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      The Pines of the Villa Borghese, Side A; The Pines near a Catacomb, Side B
    - The Pines of Rome, waxman_0408; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      The Pines of the Janiculum, Side A; The Pines of Appian Way, Side B
    - The Pines of Rome, 06/11/1956; waxman_1014; 10th anniversary performance.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 119)
    - The Pines of Rome, Mar 1962; waxman_0926; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 118)
    - The Pines of Rome, Mar 1962; waxman_0923; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 118)
    - The Pines of Rome, Mar 1962; waxman_0928; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 118)
    - The Pines of Rome, Mar 1962; waxman_0927; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 118)
    - Poem of Ecstacy, waxman_0409; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
    - Pohjola's Daughter, 12/04/1937; waxman_0172; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Polonaise in A Major, waxman_0614; Shellac disc
      Polonaise in A Major, Side A; Rakoczy March, Side B
    - Pomp and Circumstance March No. 4 in G, waxman_0340; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      Pomp and Circumstance March No. 4 in G, Side A; Pomp and Circumstance No. 1 in D, Side B
    - Possessed (1 of 5), waxman_0066; Take 1. Includes 3 copies of music mss.; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Possessed (2 of 5), waxman_0067; Take 2. Includes 3 copies of music mss.; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Possessed (3 of 5), waxman_0068; Take 3. Includes 3 copies of music mss.; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Possessed (4 of 5), waxman_0069; Take 4. Includes 3 copies of music mss.; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Possessed (5 of 5), waxman_0070; Take 5. Includes 3 copies of music mss. 8832-1-2-3C; 8835-6C; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 131)
    - Prelude A L'Apres-Midi D'un Faune, waxman_0619; Shellac disc
    - Prelude to "Oedipus Tyannus", waxman_0624; Shellac disc
    - Prelude to the Afternoon of a Faun, waxman_0348; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
    - Prelude, Arioso and Fughette on the Name of B.A.C.H.; Symphony No. 3 in D minor part 1, 6/12/1951; waxman_0848; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 116)
    - President Edvard Benes of Czechoslovakia, 09/10/1938; waxman_0232; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - President Franklin D. Roosevelt's Declaration of War, 12/08/1941; waxman_0374; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
    - President Roosevelt, 09/03/1939; waxman_0228; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - President Roosevelt's Declaration of War, waxman_0321; Shellac disc
    - Quartet No. 2 in F Sharp Minor Opus 10, waxman_0650; Privately Recorded; Shellac disc
    - Quartet No. 2 in F Sharp Minor Opus 10, waxman_0651; Privately Recorded; Shellac disc
    - Quartet No. 2 in F Sharp Minor Opus 10, waxman_0652; Privately Recorded; Shellac disc
    - Quartet No. 2 in F Sharp Minor Opus 10, waxman_0653; Privately Recorded; Shellac disc
      Part 7, Side A; Part 8, Side B
    - Quartet No. 2 in F Sharp Minor Opus 10, waxman_0654; Shellac disc
      Part 9, Side A
    - Queen Mab; Semiramides, 02/05/1938; waxman_0044; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Rebecca, 05/09/1940; waxman_0030; Air Chek; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Rebecca, waxman_0071; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Scenes 62-64, 71, 72-74
    - Rebecca, waxman_0072; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Rehearsal #1
    - Rebecca, waxman_0073; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Scenes 121, 122, 123
    - Rebecca, waxman_0074; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Scenes 130, 131, 132
    - Rebecca, waxman_0075; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Scenes 133, 134, 136
    - Rebecca, waxman_0076; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Scenes 80, 81, 82
    - Rebecca, waxman_0077; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Scenes 95, 96, 97
    - Rebecca, waxman_0078; Lacquer discs/acetates
      Scenes 103, 106, 107, 108
    - Reginald Gardiner In His Comic Monologue: Trains, waxman_0370; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      Trains, Side A; Trains, Side B
    - Reine Augen, die bezzaubern, waxman_0270; Commercial 78 rpm; Shellac disc
      Reine Augen; die Bezzaubern, Side A; Frag' ich mein beklomm'nes Herz, Side B
    - Rendezvous with Destiny, 07/19/1940; 06/06/1944; waxman_0717; Shellac disc
      Third Acceptance Speech, Side A; Prayer on D-Day, Side B